FERRAN MAYLINCH

DEVELOPER / TEACHER

ABOUT ME

I am a full-stack/mobile developer with 15+ years of experience. Despite acquiring many skills throughout my career, I believe in continuously bettering myself and enjoy learning about new technologies on a daily basis,

As a programmer, I am cooperative, disciplined and aiming for the highest standard. I enjoy challenges and discussing different approaches to achieve the best result.

I believe in delivering products that are not only functional, but also well-structured, scalable and visually pleasing.

I also love **teaching programming** in my private academy codethen.com in my spare time.

TECHNOLOGIES

- Languages: Java, JS, Android, Swift, Obj-C, Kotlin, Scala, Ruby, Python
- Frameworks: Dropwizard, Spring, Play, React, Angular, ES6, node, jQuery, Sass, RoR
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Hibernate, Redis
- IDEs: IntelliJ, Eclipse, AppCode, Atom, VS Code
- Tools: Git, Maven, Gradle, Gulp, Docker, Jenkins
- Testing: TDD, JUnit, TestNG, Mockito
- Cloud Services: AWS, Heroku, Firebase

LATEST RELEVANT POSITION

FULL STACK DEVELOPER AT GYMFORLESS

JAN 2014 - APR 2018. DEC 2018 - PRESENT

- Backend, web, mobile and dev-ops
- Technologies: Java, Android, JS, Objective-C, Swift, Dropwizard, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Play framework, Angular, node, gulp, Heroku, AWS, Quartz, IntelliJ IDEA

EDUCATION

Bs & Ms in Computer Science University of Catalonia (UPC)

1997 - 2002

Five year long **studies** of computer architecture, maths, networks, programming, logic, algorithms, data structures, compilers and electricity.

SKILLS

- Ability to deliver quality results, as well as clean and well-structured code
- Strong interest in coding both as a job and as a hobby
- Confident working in a team as well as independently
- Contributed to open source projects, e.g. JSONModel
- Created tools/libraries to help me in my work, such as LayoutHelperApp or sql-tomongo (see my GitHub)
- Worked as a **teacher**, in programming classes (Java, JavaScript, React)

CONTACT

- ferran.maylinch@gmail.com
- +34 645 804 300

OTHER RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

TEACHER AT BARCELONA TECHNOLOGY SCHOOL, IRONHACK, UBIQUM, CODE.THEN(), UPC

- Prepared content for programming, web development, craftsmanship
- **Technologies**: Java, Kotlin, Spring, Docker, JavaScript, React, Angular, HTML, CSS

CRAFTSMAN AT CODURANCE

MAY 2018 - JULY 2018

- Analysed/updated order process at Mango
- Learned about craftsmanship, TDD, Hexagonal architecture, microservices and DDD
- Technologies: Java, Spring, Jenkins, TDD, SQL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT MOBIVERY / MALCOM

JAN 2012 - JAN 2014

- Developed a cloud service providing features for mobile apps: pushes, ads, configuration
- Technologies: Java, Hibernate, DynamoDB, MySQL, AWS, Hazelcast, Tapestry

CONSULTANT AT VASS

MAY 2010 - JAN 2012

- Developed a document management webapp
- Technologies: Java, SmartGWT, Documentum

PROGRAMMER ANALYST AT TECNOCOM

JAN 2005 - MAY 2010

- Developed applications for La Caixa, CaiFor, AXA and Winterthur
- Technologies: Java, SmartGWT, Documentum